A Guide to the Nancy Florence Architectural Collection, 1954-2014
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Nancy Florence Architectural Collection, 1954-2014
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Florence, Nancy
Ms2016-007
15 Cubic Feet 9 archival boxes, 1 shoebox, 38 rolls, and 15 oversized folders
Nancy Florence was an architect based in northern California. She designed residences and studios throughout California and the Northwest. This collection documents her personal and professional activities between 1954-2014, including her architectural studies, organizational activities, travel, projects, and career with her practice, The Design Collaboration
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Nancy Florence Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in 2016.
Biographical Note
Born in Los Angeles, Nancy Florence (1935-2015) was an architectural designer based in northern California. Although Florence studied botany as an undergraduate at the University of California - Los Angeles, she became interested in architecture while abroad. She taught in Japan and used her air travel privileges - a result of her husband, Jon's, career as a pilot - to visit India and Africa. She incorporated her interest in botany into her architectural career by using landscape settings to complement buildings. After relocating to Portola Valley, CA, her first project became remodeling the family house. Florence enlisted Morgan Stedman, a prominent Palo Alto architect, as her advisor before he retired.
She was among the earliest members of the Organization of Women Architects (founded in 1973) and joined the 1975 cohort of the Women's School of Planning and Architecture at St. Joseph's College in Biddeford, Maine. She graduated from the University of California at Berkeley in 1982 with a professional degree in architecture. he was involved with the California Women in Environmental Design, an umbrella organization of the Organization of Women Architects and Design Professionals. She also served on the California Architects Board for three years after being appointed by Governor Jerry Brown in 1976, advocating for gender equity in architectural licensing. She was one of the first public members to serve on the commission. She interned at the San Luis Obispo Solar Group before opening an independent practice named "The Design Collaborative" in the 1980s. Her work included residential designs and studios throughout California and the Northwest.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the activities of Nancy Florence (1935-2015). It contains personal materials, including student work and biographical information. This collection also contains materials documenting Florence's career as an architect and founder of The Design Collaborative by representing business records, architectural drawings, design sketches, correspondences, clippings, photographs, and material catalogs related to several residential projects. Her major projects include Edgewater Residence in Blaine County, ID, Cummings Remodel in Portola Valley, CA and Shapiro Residence in Sun Valley, ID. In addition, class lecture notes, competition information, promotional materials, a wooden trusses model, and assignments from coursework at UC Berkeley and the Women's School of Planning and Architecture (WSPA) are included. In addition, the collection includes office records such as financial and administrative documents.
Arrangement
Arrangement of these materials reflects the Standard Series for Architecture and Landscape Design Records (Shepherd and Lowell). The intellectual structure reflects the following series and subseries:
Series I: Personal Papers includes biographical information, diaries, correspondence, student work, sketches, photos, and documents about Florence's travel.
Series II: Professional Papers includes corresopndence, reference files, clipings, sketches, product information, and documentation about Florence's participation in various associations (including CWED and OWA).
Series III: Course Materials includes lecture notes, research files, and student projects from Florence's studies
Series IV: Office Records includes administrative and financial records and correspondence from Florence's practice.
Series V: Project Records comprises materials specifications, sketches, correspondence, and other project records for 18 projects (primarily residential).
Series VI: Major Project - Edgewater House includes preliminary sketches, detail drawings, material schedules, site plans, photographs, nd other documentation of Florence's most significant residential project.
Series VII: Artifacts includes a set of wooden trusses models.
Index Terms
Subjects:
International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA); History of Women in Architecture; Women -- History; Women architects -- California
- Personal
  - Biographical Info
    - Curriculum Vita NF 96 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - TDC Business Cards (15) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Resume: Examples: working file (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cover Sheet Elements (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diaries
    - Small Sketchbook (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Arch Construction (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brown Spiral Bound Sketchbook - Strathmore (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Small "Lil' Comp" notebook - 6 x 3 1/4" (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Loose sheets taken from spiral bind sketchbook. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Loose pages - sketches (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence
    - Printed page - "Celebrating Ourselves and Our Work by Contributing to Herstory (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Work
    - Perspective exercises (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Image Analyses (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Berkeley: Admission Statement of Purpose Statement of Purpose for Admission into M.Arch program at University of California - November 1978 Contains biographical sketch" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Travel
    - Travel Articles (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ARCH: Museums, Exhibitions, bldgs in other cities (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arch Travels (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Travel Notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Travel Architecture (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sketches
    - Napkin sketch (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Paper construct (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Graphics Stationary (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Jonathan Marvel Cabin in/near Stanley (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bookcase - Freedman / Grey (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cartoons etc. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "General Notes Loose papers" (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Cartoons - drwg set checklist (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Landscape Steps (1994) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Photos
    - Loose Photos #1 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Arch Gardens, Foreign, USA (Photo Box) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Professional
  - Correspondence
    - Initial Client letters of agreement *desc of work - CB Crumb (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - MTG Notes Ryan / Baldwin (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Baldwin Engineering (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Berk Bldg Inspector" (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Nana Door Det" (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Email Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Tile 6225 - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - CWED - CA Women in Environmental Design (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Energy & Architects Catalogue (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - George (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Reg Review & Responses (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Client Contracts Agreement (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ken's Suggestions (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Sylvan Company Agreement (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Abbreviated Form of Agreement Between Owner and Contractor (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Binder of agenda/measurements/files (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Georgianna Greenwood EW Letter for Steel (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Mechanics' Lien Notices (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Client References-Admire Construction List of references, resumes, business cards" (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Structural Transmittals (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Construction Memos (1993) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Transmittal to Shapiros (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Associations
    - Binder Organization of Women Architects + Design Professionals (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Awards
    - Small Sketchbook - Morilla Clipper Sketch Book (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - CWED / Parthenia Award (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art Competition - folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - American Wood Council 1996 Wood Design Award Competition (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Water Heaters: Past, Present, and Future - Certificate of Completion (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Matison Day 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - North Gate Competition (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - North Gate Site Plan (Map-case 22, Folder 1)
    - Cummings Competition (Map-case 22, Folder 2)
  - Reference Files - Clippings
    - Fine Homebuilding Magazine (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Portfolio (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Clothes/ Fashion (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Tile Design (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Current Gardening (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Picture File temp (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Envelope - Nancy dining RM light (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Tables & Flowers (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Table Settings (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Arch Examiners CBAE Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Lamp Lighting (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Paints & Finishes (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Carpentry & General (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Building, Maintenance (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Floor Plans (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Flooring Carpets (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Furniture, Bookcases (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Garden Paving (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Plumbing Electrical (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ideas (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Interiors (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Kitchens (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Infill Housing Alternative Housing (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Lighting Design Inspiration (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Caulking Sealants (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Technical Info (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Internet Research (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Images (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Bamboo (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Reference Files - Sketches
    - Desk Crit UC Berkeley - 1980 drwgs by Joe Escherick (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Welding Project Ideas. Fountains, sculpture (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Arbor 83 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Vellum Detail Templates (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Details Reference SLOSG (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Working Drawings and Info (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Floor Plan Studies (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Waterproofing details (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Details (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Houston Lantern (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Bench @ Loft (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Construction Bulletins #1-5 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Paquette Info Communication (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - V. Marten Arastek Original Vellums (Box 11)
  - Reference Files - Product Info
    - Old Research for RAB (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Energy (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Lighting Techniques (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Architecture Menu (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Appropriate Technology (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Acoustics (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Acoustic Wall Treatment (Floor & Ceiling) (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Model Welded Wire Trellis Information (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Fixture Cut Sheets (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Flashings (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Tech Aids/Info (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Copper Roofing (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Soils Geology (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Deck & Flashing (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Arch Administration (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Paint, Floor, Finish Info (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Electronic/Security/Telephone (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Floors, FLR Covering (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Glass windows (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - American ALDES Ventilation Corporation (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hot Tub Info (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Landscape/Courtyard Lighting (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Lantern/Porches (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Paint Issues (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Arch Color/Paint (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - HVAC Equip (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Quality STDs and H2O (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Wine Referg (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Tile Patterns, Resources (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Stone & Ceramic Tile (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hardware Application Info (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Cabinetry (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Concrete Finishes (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Toilet/Bath Accessories (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Chimney Cap Screen (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Lighting Info REF (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Lanterns Sketches / Lighting Designs (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Acoustics Building Details (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - CBS Notes Examples Hardware Formulation & Organization (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Luminaires General (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Lighting cut sheets/Schedules (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Luminaire Resource/Design (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lighting Fixtures (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Plumbing Cut Sheets-Final 7/10/93 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Cut Sheets Plumbing 2/24/94 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Operation and installation booklets (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Lighting w/ Alice Notes (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Equipment List and Cutsheets (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Dead File SU to OAK (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Reference Files
    - "Rachel Remodel Cut Sheets" (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Measuring plane grids for perspetives (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Books (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Hal Levin Board Meeting Feburary 15, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - In House Meeting notes/HAC (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Sun Charts, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Source Addresses (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Next Time Notes (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Faculty Papers
  - Course Materials
    - Class Notes - Lecture Notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lectures 01 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1980-81: Studio 202 Fall 81 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Arch Design Exam (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Spiral Bound WSPA 1975-2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Paper "San Xavier del Bac" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Composition Book - History of Architecture I - Kostoff (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Arch. Prof. & WSPA (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Portfolio Prints of Schoolwork 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Past Problems & Programs Berkeley 1979 - 82 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Repro Info (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Kostoff. Towns & Cities (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - ED 170 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Theory, Arch - Polit Educational Aesthetic (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Former Classes (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Arch 269 A (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Chris Alexander Studio - S '81. Notes on Structural, office building (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Class Material (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Folder with class notes (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Arch History (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Arch Ed - CSM Design Class Project Statements " (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Thesis Project Drawings (Box 12)
    - Projects from Arch 200 UC Berkeley 1979-82 (Map-case 22, Folder 4)
    - Arch 200 Studio Project (Map-case 22, Folder 5)
  - Research Files (Box 5)
    - Reflections on Practice Archit (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Arch Library Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Arch Library (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Student Work
    - Technical Guide: Natural Wood Siding (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Small brochure: A Harmony of Light and Form. Enhanced Through Shojis (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Library for the Community and the Visually Handicapped (Box 13)
    - UC Botanic Garden Info Center Nursery (Box 14)
    - Chris Alexander Studio (Box 15)
- Office Records (Box 5)
  - Administrative
    - ARCH Office Mgt (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Services: Statements. Time sheets. Daily Records. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Spec Info (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - CBAE Licensing History (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Code Notes - City of Berkeley Req Zoning (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Zoning/Permits (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - City of Berkeley Permits & Sample Bldg Details (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Owner/contractor Forms (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Drilling Report (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Corkboard (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Office Management (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Septic/Health Info (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Water Drilling and Soil (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence
    - Bay Area - Bldg Resources (Box 5)
  - Financial Records
    - "Sort & File" (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - file with 2006 Office expenses (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Val Mastercard 2011 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - VBS Stockrecord treasury direct records in garage files (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Invoice (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Hardware + Mirrors (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - HAC Lighting (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Plumbing (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Purchase Orders EW (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Roofing (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Budget/EW (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Professional Expenses-Inkstone Constructions (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - TDC 1991-02 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - TDC 1991-03 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - TDC 1991-04 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - TDC 1991-05 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - TDC 1991-06 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - TDC 1991-07 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Bay Commercial-Boyd Receipts (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Shapiro Residence: Budgets and Invoices (1/5) (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Shapiro Residence: Budgets and Invoices (2/5) (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Shapiro Residence: Budgets and Invoices (3/5) (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Shapiro Residence: Budgets and Invoices (4/5) (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Shapiro Residence: Budgets and Invoices (5/5) (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Publications Order Form: Design Collaborative (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Project Records
  - Shapiro Residence
    - Facsimile Transmission - Plumbing (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Shapiro Sketches / Ideas (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Shapiro Residence - Task List (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Shapiro Residence: Model Specification (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Shapiro Residence: Model Specification #2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ironwork Fireplace Surround (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Info and Paint Specs (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Permits/Zoning (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Trellis Shapiro Veranda (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Shapiro Trellis 97 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ventilation Plan Shapiro (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Reduced Plans (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Landscape/Site (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Miller/Shapiro Contract Statements (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Paint Color Schedule (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Miller/Shapiro-Detailed Sketches (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Shapiro Residence: Fireplace (1992) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Paint Info: B. Moore (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Plumbing: Obsolete Info (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - House Sketches (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Windows (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Landscape Plan: Courtyard Shapiro (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Shapiro Residence: Detailed Plans and Sketches (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Specifications: Info Sheets (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Shapiro Residence: Schedules (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Shapiro Residence: Correspondence with Ralph (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Baker Residence
    - Hardware + Appliance (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Detail reference for RAB WD Set (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Floorplan sketch (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Stickeybacks: The Design Collaborative (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - For Permit Drawings (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Nancy's Kitchen (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Rab Remodel Obsolete (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Obsolete Sketches Already Copied (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Wayside Photos (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Additions to the Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Baker: 748 Wayside Road, Portola Valley (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - RA Baker Residence (Box 16)
    - RA Baker Residence #2 (Box 17)
    - RA Baker Residence #3 (Box 18)
    - Examples and Details for RAB Project (Map-case 22, Folder 6)
  - Martin Remodel
    - "V. Martin" (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Design Sketches Martin 2001 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Martin Improvemet Blueprint (Box 19)
    - Veronica Martin Residence (Box 20)
  - Baldwin Residence
    - "Best in east bay" (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Orig Details Baldwin 06 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "Baldwin RFI's" (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Consultant Invoices (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Preliminary questions concerning Baldwin Residence (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Amit Metal Fabricators Drawings (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - The Design Collaborative drawing (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Baldwin Invoices (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Baldwin Project Files (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Lockwood Perspective Grids (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Window Details and Memorandum (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Baldwin Residence: Elevation Sketches (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Baldwin Residence: Steel Balcony Addition (Box 21)
    - Baldwin Residence: Steel Balcony Addition Dimensions (Box 22)
    - Florence Residence Additions (Box 23)
  - Cummings Residence
    - Houston Cummings: Folder with Sketches (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sketch Ideas to Transfer (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cummings Materials Specs (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Job File Cummings/Finley 94 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Building sketch (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cummings 12/91 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bath Garden (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Preliminary Details Vellums (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - HAC Bath Details (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Houston Cummings Addition Financial Analysis (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Specifications: Cummings/Finley Addition (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Site Memos/Field Reports (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Composition Notebook "Cummings #2" (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Cummings/Finley Contract Time Sheets (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Cummings Specifications (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Cummings/Finley 3D Sketches (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cummings Details Copies (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Construction/remodel papers (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Fireplace (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Cummings Permit 5/90 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Remodel (E) Cummings (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Cummings Composition Book (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Drawings for Cummings Residence (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Cummings Transfers (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Additions to Cummings/Finley Residence (Box 24)
    - Cummings Original Prints (Box 25)
    - Additions to Cummings/Finley Residence - April 1991 (Box 26)
    - Remodel of Cummings & Finley Residence (Box 27)
    - Remodel of Cummings & Finley Residence #2 (Box 28)
    - Collyer & Cummings Residence (Map-case 22, Folder 7)
    - Cummings/Finley Residence Plans (Map-case 22, Folder 8)
  - Milshap House
    - Milshap House I 1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Milshap House (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Oliver House
    - Prelimary Oliver House Blueprint (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Oliver Blueprint (Box 29)
    - Oliver Blueprint #2 (Box 30)
  - Shirley Gate
    - Shirley's Steel Gate fabricated by Treven 2005/2006 Drawings & Notes (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Shirley Overhangs @ 252 Avondale Fall 02 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Drawings for New Outdoor Cooking Center (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Shirley's Gate 2005 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Shirley Paint EW (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Shirley 252 Avondale (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Shirley Guest Cabinets Table Window Seat (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Jenkins Garage
    - Project Management Info (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Model Specs (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Open Hand Kitchen
    - CWED Exhibit - Project Open Hand Kitchen (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Ken Haggard
    - Building Details Ken Haggard (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Instruction Detail Meth - Kitchen, Stair Organization (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Wheeler and Hoffman Residences (Box 31)
  - Aratesh Records
    - Arasteh Project 5/96 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Arasteh-Henderson Residence: Alcove and Steel Balcony Addition (Box 32)
  - Buck Residence
    - 2004 | 6225 Concepts - Deck, Garden, Kitchen, Bookshelves (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Trellis Gate - 6225 Hillegas (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Bench & Garden 6/08 - 6225 D.R. Garden (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Neff Residence
    - Mitchell Neff Sketches (Box 33)
  - Wurster House
    - Gregory Wurster Farmhouse (Box 34)
    - Wurster-Husum House (Box 35)
  - Wiggins/Woodard Studio
    - Wiggins and Woodard Studio (Box 36)
  - Henry Street
    - 1233 Henry Street (Box 37)
  - George
    - George 2010-2011 (Map-case 22, Folder 9)
- Major Projects - Edgewater
  - Reference Files
    - Edgewater House - Task Book 1/2 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Composition Notebook - Edgewater Specs 7/92 (Box 7, Folder 45)